welcome to the machine learning for students series
欢迎来到机器学习系列课程
today's lessons on cyber security
今天的课程主题是网络安全
I hope you're excited because I am
我希望你很高兴 因为我很高兴
let's go
让我们出发吧
now good place to start when we talk
当我们了解网络安全
about cybersecurity is how they actually
一个好的开始就是知道它们内部工作原理
work internally if you're as curious as I am
如果你和我一样好奇
you can take a look at this video to find out
你可以看看这个视频
antivirus software is like a
杀毒软件就好像
doctor for your computer it can protect
计算机的医生 它可以保护
your computer from getting viruses or it
计算机收到病毒的侵扰
can help remove a virus once your
也可以在电脑受到病毒侵扰之后杀除病毒
computer's been infected new viruses are
新病毒总是源源不断的
coming out all the time and it's the job
杀毒软件的工作就是
antivirus software to help keep us protected
防病毒 保护电脑
just like you go to the doctor
就像每年你都需要看医生
every year your computer needs to be
你的电脑都需要定期
checked by an anti-virus software
接受防病毒软件的检查
regularly to make sure that it's healthy
以确保它健康
some of you might be wondering hmm where
你们有些人可能想知道
did antivirus really get started well
人们什么时候开始用杀毒软件的
I'm gonna let you know right now
我现在就告诉你
John McAfee was instrumental in
约翰 迈克菲在杀毒软件商业化中
commercializing antivirus software
起到了重要的作用
he founded the first software company
他在1987年成立了第一家软件公司
McAfee associates in 1987 that were
迈克菲公司
specifically focused for commercializing
它专注于杀毒软件商业化
antivirus software he really wanted to
他真的想要
make sure that everyone's computers were
确保每个人的电脑
able to get detected and protected
能够被检测和保护
against all those threats that were
以防受到病毒威胁
coming out he was very important in
在确保你的电脑安全方面
making sure that your computers were safe
他功不可没
before we go ahead and get into
在我们继续了解
what antivirus does let's talk a little
杀毒软件具体做什么之前
bit about the different types of viruses that are out
让我们讲讲不同类型的病毒
there now you can see some
你可以看到
of the pictures of those viruses behind me
在我身后有一些病毒的图片
Trojan horse viruses pretend to be something
木马病毒利用伪装
to get into your computer
进入你的电脑
there's also viruses out there that
还有其他病毒
actually pretend to be antivirus
假装是防病毒软件
software and pretend to protect you against them
假装能够保护你
but they're actually viruses
但一旦点击它们
once you click on them
它们的病毒本性暴露无遗
then we have malware malware gets into your
恶意软件进入电脑之后
computer and tries to just damage or
会试图破坏
disable your computer
禁用你的电脑
we have worm attacks which replicate themselves
蠕虫会复制自己
and attack other computers once they've
一旦进入你的计算机
gotten into your own
它们会攻击其他计算机
there is boot viruses that go after
引导区病毒会跟随
the Master Boot Record of your computer hard drive
计算机硬盘驱动器的主引导记录
there's android-specific malware out there
安卓的恶意软件病毒
that goes right after Android operating systems
专门进入安卓操作系统
now it might seem like there's a lot of viruses
似乎看起来有好多病毒
but this is actually only just a few of them
但这只是冰山一角
you'll find out later
之后你会看到
how many viruses are out there
更多的病毒
and how quickly they keep coming out
以及它们更新的速度之快
don't worry though
不要担心
antivirus is right on the case of
保障电脑的安全
making sure that you're protected
杀毒软件绝对是不二选择
so let's go into a little bit more detail
让我们更加具体了解
about the specific types of viruses out there
一些特性类型的病毒
let's start with the worm
让我们从蠕虫病毒开始吧
if you might think worm are what you use to
你觉得虫子是用来捕鱼的
catch fish but actually in the world of viruses
但是在病毒的世界里
they're very serious
它们威力巨大
a worm is a type of virus that infects
蠕虫病毒通过网络
other computers across the network
感染其他计算机
by exploring vulnerabilities
它会发现计算机中的漏洞
like weak passwords to get in
比如弱密码 进入计算机
if they've been successful at getting into the computer
如果它们成功进入计算机
it allows remote access and code execution
它会允许远程访问  代码执行
while file sharing is enabled
同时启用文件共享
it might even also spread via removable
它甚至可能通过移动设备
devices and weak administrator passwords
弱管理员密码进行传播
now worms are really bad what they do is
蠕虫真的很糟糕  它们会
disable important system services and security protocols
禁用重要的系统服务以及安全协议
you don't want a bunch of worms
你肯定不想一群蠕虫
crawling around your computer that's for sure
在你计算机里蠕动
the next type of virus that we're going to be
我们要谈论下一个病毒是
talking about is a polymorphic virus sounds cool right
多态病毒  听起来很酷 不是吗
it's definitely not
当然不是
a polymorphic virus is kind of like a worm
多态病毒很像蠕虫
except that it's encrypted
除了它是加密的
and the reason why it's encrypted because of
加密的原因是在于
polymorphic virus attempts to avoid being scanned or detected
多态病毒可以避免被扫描或检测
now once your computer is infected by polymorphic virus
一旦你的计算机被多态病毒感染
it duplicates itself by creating
它会复制自己
it usable but slightly different modified copies
但会稍有不同
and then performs all the same malicious things
然后执行所有和蠕虫病毒
that a worm would have to your computer
相同的恶意操作
the next type of virus we're going to talk about
我们要讲的下一种类型的病毒
is Android malware
是安卓恶意病毒
it's malware specifically designed for Android operating systems
它专为安卓操作系统而设计
this type of malware is able to do things
这款恶意软件能在你手机上操作
on your mobile phone without you knowing about it
但是你完全不知道
so imagine there could be a virus on your mobile phone
请想象你的手机里有病毒
on your cell phone without you knowing
而你完全不知道
and it could be sharing information
它能在你不知情的情况下
without your acknowledge
分享你的信息
these types of viruses have become
这种类型的病毒
more difficult to deal with
更难处理
because wireless phones and PDA network
因为无线手机 PDA网络
have become more common and they've grown in complexity
越来越普遍 而这些病毒越来越复杂
the viruses out there that are designed
这些专为安卓系统设计的
for Android systems are evolving at a quick pace
病毒正飞速进化着
the next virus we're going to talk about
我们要讲的下一个病毒
is actually going to take us back
将要把我们带回去一点点
a little bit one step before the Android bomber
回到安卓恶意软件前
and that's the regular malware virus
它就是常规的恶意软件病毒
some of you might have been wondering at this point
这时候你们有些人可能就觉得奇怪了
what is malware actually mean well
恶意软件到底是什么
malware means malicious software and
恶意软件是蓄意破坏的软件
it's any programmer file that's harmful to a computer user
它是任何有害于计算机使用者的程序文件
now that seems like a very broad definition
看起来似乎定义太过宽泛
but the different types of malware actually narrow it down
但是不同类型的恶意软件能限定它
so the Android malware that we just
所以我们刚谈到的安卓恶意病毒
talked about is a subset of a malware virus
只是恶意病毒的一部分
now once malware is installed in your computer
一旦你的计算机中安装了恶意软件
it performs unwanted tasks
它会执行你不希望执行的任务
malware itself is actually mainly designed to
恶意软件本身旨在
transmit information about your web activity
传递网页活动的信息
to a third party
给第三方
so people who want to snoop around
所以想要窥探你
and find out what you're doing
想要知道你在做什么的人
typically want to use malware to infect your
一般会用恶意软件进行干扰
computer to get that information from you
从你的计算机中获取信息
next we're going to talk about the
接下来我们谈谈
technical stages of malware
恶意软件的技术阶段
I bet some of you were wondering
你们一定很想知道
well how does it actually work
恶意软件怎么工作的
now we're going to get into some details here
我们现在就来具体讲讲
that might seem a little confusing
但可能你会听晕
so if you have to go ahead and rewind that's okay
所以如果你一会儿要倒回去再看一遍 完全ok
now what you see here behind me
在我身后有一张图
is a diagram of how malware works
上面描述了恶意软件如何工作
malware can get into your computer
恶意软件可以进入你的计算机
through say a weak password
通过 比如说 一个弱密码
once it's in it performs a statistical analysis on
一旦进入 它就会对你的系统
your system to see if it's interested in
进行数据分析
taking a closer look at a target file
寻找感兴趣的目标文件
now if it's found that file that it
如果找到该文件
mounts to take a closer look at it then
然后它就会细细分析
performs a dynamic analysis on it and
对它执行动态分析
what it's doing is examining ecstatic properties
它正在做的就是检查属性
so those things about the filethat don't necessarily move
所以文件不一定会被移动
after that it performs an analysis
然后 它会对文件储存
on the memory of the file and how the files being used
进行分析 比如你如何使用文件
or how you're dialing on your phone
如何打电话
or who you're sending text messages to
和谁发消息
once it's collected all that memory analysis
一旦这些信息被收集
and then sends it back to the person
它们就会被发送给
that sent the Malheur to you in the first place
那个把恶意软件装在你电脑上的人
and they now have access to that data and information
他们就有权限得到你的信息数据
and can use it against you
并且使用它 对你不利
if at this point you think
如果此时你认为
oh man there are so many viruses and
哦 天呐 有这么多病毒
they can really get me
他们真能搞死我
how am I gonna help myself well don't worry
我怎么自救啊 别着急
your computers and your phones and your PDAs
你的电脑 手机 PDA
they're all safe
他们其实很安全
there are many different companies out there
有不同的公司
like the ones that we see here behind me that
比如说我身后这些
have developed software using machinelearning
开发了软件 利用机器学习
to help protect you and if you
保护你的设备
remember our friend McAfee right here
如果你还记得我们的老朋友 McAfee
their company's still around too and
他们的公司仍旧在运行
they can help you out
他们可以帮助你
so let's talk a little bit about
所以我们现在来谈谈
why dynamic malware analysis is mainly used
为什么动态分析会被用到
or what it is in the first place
首先动态分析到底是什么
this may all start something a little bit confusing to you
这可能一开始有点绕
right well don't worry about it
不过别担心
we're gonna break it down
我们会一步一步来
so dynamic or behavior analysis is performed
所以动态或行为分析
by observing the behavior of a malware
是通过观察恶意软件
while actually running on a whle system
在整个系统中如何运作
all right so what does that even mean
这又是什么意思
let's break it down
让我们分解它
first think about it like this
首先 你可以这么想
if you play sports you practice right
如果你参加体育竞赛 你得练习对吧
you might even scrimmage against your own teammates
你甚至可能会和队友们打比赛
to see how you would perform during an actual game
预测自己在实际比赛中的表现
well that's what we're doing here
这与动态分析的道理一样
when we're trying to learn about how malware affects the computer
当我们理解恶意软件 如何影响我们的电脑时
we're practicing and we're practicing against ourselves
我们不断练习与自己对抗
what we do is we practice and we practice on a non labeled data set
我们在一组无标记的数据集合中练习
when we figure out how we think it works
当我们弄清楚恶意软件大概怎么运作时
you go ahead and label it and then use that label data
我们便标记 运用标签数据
to help protect ourselves against real attacks
保护自身免于真正的袭击
just like that scrimmage against your own team
就好像队里面自己的练习
helps you prepare for the big game
帮助你准备大型比赛一样
dynamic malware analysis is used to help prepare antivirus
动态恶意软件分析 用于对抗病毒
against protecting you against the real thing
保护你的计算机
now that you know a little bit about how anti viruses work
现在你简单知道了防病毒软件如何工作
a little bit about the viruses themselves
了解了病毒本身
what are some real-world examples of malware attacks
现实生活中病毒袭击是怎么样的呢
we're going to go over three here
我们现在要举三个例子
to help give you an idea of how they've actually been used
来帮助你理解它们如何运作
the first one we're going to talk about is one called wanna cry
我们要谈的第一个病毒叫做 wanna cry
it was done the biggest malware attack in history
它是历史上最大规模的一次病毒袭击
now wanna cry wasn't talking about physically crying
wanna cry不是说真的让你哭
although some people who were affected by it certainly wanted to
虽然一些被影响的人可能真的想哭
what did was in fact almost a quarter million computers
它攻击了来自150个不同的国家
across 150 different countries
将近25万台电脑
when it was unleashed in May of 2012
自2012年5月被释放以来
that's a big attack
这是一个巨大的袭击
now the next one we're goingto talk about is a little bit older
我们接下来讨论的这个有点老了
it was called Stuxnet
它叫Stuxnet
Stuxnet was deployed through USB flash drive
它通过USB闪存驱动器
infecting software controlling centrifuges and
影响软件控制离心机
a nuclear facility in Iran
和伊朗核设施
that's really serious and had the potential to be really dangerous
这真是非常严重并且可能引发危险
the last one we're going to talk about is mydoom and
最后一个要谈的是mydoom
it's the oldest one we're talking about
它是3个例子中最老的一个
it came out in 2004 and
它出现在2004年
it earned the title of the fastest spreading malware in history
随后得到“史上最快传播恶意软件”的恶名
using email subject lines like error
它利用电子邮件主题行 如显示错误
and mail delivery system
和邮件交付系统
because those were ones that were likely to be clicked on
因为那些很可能被人点击
and once people clicked on those emails
一旦人们点击这些电子邮件
it enticed users to open it
它会诱惑用户打开
and pinballed across the web at speeds reportedly affecting
以影响16％到25％的电子邮件的速度
16 to 25 percent of all emails at the time
迅速在网上传播
that means someone on your street
这意味着与你同一街道
someone in your neighborhood at some point 2004
在你家附近的的人在2014年
likely was affected by mydoom
很可能收到了mydoom的影响
now that you have some real-world examples
我现在有了一些现实生活中
of malware attacksunder your belt
恶意软件攻击的例子
we're gonna move on and get deeper
我们要继续深入了解
into what viruses really are
病毒究竟是什么
let's talk a little bit about how fast
让我们先简单谈谈
new malware viruses are coming out
新的恶意病毒的出现速度
there's an institute called the AV test Institute
有家叫做AV test Institute的机构
what they do is they register new malicious programs every day
他们的工作就是每天发现新恶意软件程序
they estimate that there's about a quarter million
他们估计每天大约有
new malwareprograms being released every single day
25万新的恶意软件被释放
now they go ahead and analyze these viruses
他们接着用sunshine或者V test
using tools like sunshine and V test
分析这些病毒
and the new viruses are classified
根据病毒的特点
according to their characteristics
进行分类
and then they're logged
然后记录保存
it's just like when scientists find out a new version of the flu
这就好像当科学家发现了一个新的流感病毒
they want to go ahead and save that
要继续保存它
so that they can understand it for the future
为未来病毒理解做好基础
now part of the esra program
在部分的ESRA项目中
they analyzed more than 55 million emails
研究者分析了超过5500万封电子邮件
and they found that over 9,000 contain dangerous file types
他们发现超过9,000封含有危险文件类型
and of those 9,000
在这9000封之中
about 1,800 of those were known viruses
有1800封含有已知病毒
and about 700 were unknown
700封含有未知病毒
and they contained malware attachments
它们包含恶意软件附件
that's pretty big considering how many
这是相当大的
emails are sent every minute of every day
考虑到每天有多少封邮件被发出
we've spent a lot of time talking about
我们花了不少时间谈论了
what malware is
什么是恶意软件
a little bit about how it works
它如何工作
and gave you some real examples of what viruses have done
并给你一些真实的病毒袭击例子
but what is a cyberattack
但是什么是网络攻击
anyways well let's break it down for you
让我们慢慢道来
a cyber attacks is an attack that is launched
网络袭击是
from one computer or more computers
一台计算机或更多计算机
against another computer or multiple computers or networks
对另一台计算机或多台 或者网络的袭击
just like our friend here there's
就像我们这里的朋友
someone sitting behind the computer
有人坐在电脑后面
sending out a malware virus with the
发出恶意软件病毒
intent to do some harm to someone else's network or computer
意图伤害他人的网络或计算机
now cyber attacks can be broken down into two broad types
网络攻击可以依据目标可分为两大类
where the goals are to disable a target
一类的目标是 禁用目标电脑
computer are knocking off line or
或者让他们下线
attacks where the goal is to get access
另一类的目标是获取访问权限
to the target computers data and perhaps
得到目标计算机数据
gain administrative privileges to it so
甚至获得管理权限
you can think about it like this they
你可以这样理解
want to break down your computer so that
一类是让你电脑死机
you can't use it or they want to take
所以你不能使用它 或者它想要
information from the computer so that
你计算机中的信息
they can use it for their own purposes
他们可以用于私人目的
that's what a cyberattack is
这就是网络攻击
now we just finished talking about what a cyber attack is
现在我们说完了网络攻击是什么
and what we're gonna do now is
我们现在要做的是
get into some details on a specific kind
具体了解特定类型的网络攻击
the botnet
僵尸网络
now what does the word botnet actually mean
什么是僵尸网络
well the word itself comes
它由两个词组成
from two different words robot and network
机器人（robot）和网络（network）
now cyber criminals use special Trojan viruses
网络罪犯利用特殊的木马病毒
to breach the security of several users computers
越过一些用户的防火墙
once they've done this
一旦他们得手
they take over the computers
他们便接管了计算机
and organize all of the infected
他们将被操控的计算机
machines into a network of bots that the
结成一个僵尸网络
criminals can remotely manage it's
犯罪分子便可以远程管理它
basically slaving out all the different machines
它相当于奴役许多台计算机
and using that as a one hosted network
利用它们
for their own malicious purposes
达成自己邪恶的目的
now we're going to talk about another type of attack
现在我们要谈另一种类型的袭击
ransomware attack
勒索软件攻击
ransomware attack it's actually like it sounds
勒索软件攻击意思和字面一样
it holds your computer for ransom
它勒索你的计算机
what happens is once the virus gets into your computer
一旦病毒进入你的计算机
it locks you out from your own data and information
它会锁住你的数据与信息
it tells you that in order to get access
并告诉你 为了重新获得访问权限
back to your data and back to your information
得到你的数据与信息
that you have to pay it a ransom
你必须付它赎金
usually it requests these ransoms back from you in the form of a crypto currency
赎金通常形式为加密货币
like Bitcoin even after you've paid
比如比特币 但是就算你付钱了
the cybercriminal they may not give
网络犯罪分子可能也不会
you access to your data back
将数据信息还给你
ransomware attacks are no fun to deal with
赎金攻击并不好玩
oK we've spent a lot of time talking about viruses
我们花了很多时间谈论病毒
and we've spent some time talking about what antivirus is now
现在我们要花了一些时间 谈论杀毒软件
where does machine learning come into play
机器学习在此过程中扮演着怎样的角色
well machine learning actually helps us
机器学习实际上帮助我们
put the fight back against the virus
反击病毒的攻击
and how does it do this
它是如何做到的
well machine learning techniques are used to detect odd behavior
机器学习可以用来检测奇怪的行为
and prevent further spread of viruses
并防止病毒进一步传播
artificial intelligence is involved
人工智能在其中
and tries to make decisions about whether or not
要做出决定
analyzed code is harmful based on a
依据代码的一系列特征
series of the traits of that code now
分析它是否有害
some traits might rank higher than others
一些特质的危险性可能高于其他
so the code that's determined to
所以可以通过代码来检测恶意病毒
am I not good I might have some traits
但有些软件会说 “我不好吗？
that the software considers to be possible indications of malware
我可能有恶意病毒的特征”
bt don't worry the artificial intelligence
不用担心 人工智能
tries really hard to make sure that it
会尽量保证
only detects those viruses that are going to be harmful into computer
只检测对电脑有害的病毒
we're gonna get into the various techniques
我们要进入机器学习
used by machine learning for antivirus building
用于杀毒软件的一些方式
and they've come into two major categories
他们分可为两大类
on the one hand you have anomaly detection
一类是异常检测
that's what we just talked about a little earlier
就是我们刚刚讲到的
and then on the other hand you have Bayesian classification
另一类是贝叶斯分类
we're going to get intodetail on that one a little later
我们稍后会详细介绍那个
so I hope you're excited to figure out
希望你很高兴知道
how machine learning actually helps fight the virus
机器学习是如何打败病毒的
how is the nomally detection used for virus detection
异常检测是如何进行的
well it scans code for unusual behavior
它扫描查找异常行为
and when it finds a piece of unusual behavior
当它发现异常行为
which we call an outlier
我们称它为异常值，
it flags it as a potential virus
它将其标记为潜在的病毒
and what it tries to do is identify patterns
它在做的其实就是
that don't conform to expected behavior
识别与预期不同的模式
people who make anomaly detection software actually admit that
那些创造异常检测的人承认
there are some attck that they allowed to go through on a network
有一些攻击是没办法检测出来的
because they can't get everything
因为他们并不拥有所有信息
now this means that hundreds of machines
这意味着数以百计的计算机
are being compromised before an attack is detected
在检测之前 可能已经受到攻击
once it's detected it's isolated
一旦检测出异常 它将被孤立
and your system is protected from it
你的系统将受到保护
okay now we've gone through an Amelie detection
好啦 我们现在已经讲完艾米莉检测啦
the next major category if you remember is Bayesian classifiers
下一个要讲的 如果你还记得 是贝叶斯分类器
that there's a lot of math coming up in these next two slides
在接下来的两页幻灯片中  会有很多的数学
so you have to rewind and re-watch that's okay
如果你要倒带重看 完全没问题
I'm actually going to take a step out of the screen for a minute
在接下里的几分钟里 我要先从屏幕上消失
so that you can see everything as I go through this
这样在我讲的时候 你就能看到全部内容
first let's talk about what a Bayesian classifier is
我们首先谈谈什么是贝叶斯分类器
a Bayesian classifier calculates probabilities for every different event
贝叶斯分类器计算每一个不同事件的概率
here in the example that we're going to be using in these next two slides
在这两页的幻灯片中
we're really going to be talking about two things
我们将会谈论两个东西
smoke and fire
烟雾和火灾
what we do is we figure out the probability
我们要弄清楚的就是
of smoke given that there's fire
看到烟雾 有火的概率
that first bullet there
屏幕上的第一个标记处
where you see the P with a bar then a B
你可以看到P（a|b）
that's the probability of a given the probability of B
它的意思是在B情况下a的概率是多少
now when we talk about a
我们谈论的a
what we really need is fire
也就是火
so if you want it in your head and you want to put in fire for a
如果你想在你脑海中记住 a就是火
you're more than welcome to do that
那再好不过了
the example that we have here is
我们接下来要做的
we're going to try and find out the
就是尝试找出
probability of fire given that we see smoke
看到烟雾情况下火灾的概率
and we find this out by knowing
通过知道
what the probabilities of smoke and fire are
烟和火的概率
and then doing a little bit of math
然后做一些计算
to figure out the probability of fire
我们便可以得出
given that me see smoke
看到烟雾情况下火灾的概率
okay so these are the basic things that we're looking at
这是我们寻找的基本的东西
but I want you to take a moment
但是我想让你停下来
to observe this slide
仔细看看这张幻灯片
read it through and think about it
仔细阅读并且好好想一想
on the next slide we're actually going to
在下一页幻灯片中 我们将要
go through a step by step example using our smoke and fire
一步步的讲解烟与火的例子
so that you really understand what a Bayesian classifier is
以便你真正理解贝叶斯分类器
I'm here even though you can't see me now
我在这里 虽然你现在看不到我
I'm gonna walk you through this step by step
我将带你一步步分解问题
the question is when I see smoke
问题是看到烟雾的时候
what's the chance that there's also going to be fire
有火的概率是多大呢
I'm going to break it down for you
听我仔细道来
first let's talk about the top half of the screen
首先让我们来谈谈的屏幕上半部分
then we're going to talk about the bottom half
然后我们再谈谈下半部分
the top half of the screen gives us information that we know about
屏幕上半部分告诉我们一些信息
so let's talk about the probability of fire given that there's smoke
所以让我们来谈谈在有烟情况下有火的概率
we know that there's a 90% chance that fire can create smoke
我们知道有火情况下有烟的可能性是90％
we also know that there's a 10% chance of there just being fire without smoke
我们也知道有火情况下无烟的概率是10%
and a 1% chance that you can create smoke without fire
有烟却没有火的概率是1%
knowing those three things we can find out the
知道这三样东西 我们便可以
probability of there being smoke given that we see a fire
得出有火情况下有烟的概率
but what we're gonna do is
我们接下来
we're gonna say P of smoke with the bar fire
会说P（smoke|fire）
which basically means the probability of smoke given that there's a fire
它的意思是有火情况下有烟的概率
it is gonna be 1% that's our chance of just smoke
有烟没有火的概率是1%
multiplied by 90% which is
乘以90％ 即是
our chance that there's fire given that there is  smoke
有烟情况下有火
over 10%
除以10％
which is our chance of they're just being fire
即 有火却无烟
now if we do the math what we come up with
我们进行计算 便可得出
is a 9% chance of there being smoke when there's fire
9% 有火情况下有烟的概率
now like I said if you have to rewind and go over this again
如果你需要倒带重看一遍
until you understand it that's okay
知道你彻底理解 完全没问题
I know that we just went over something pretty tough
我们刚刚学习了非常难的知识
great job everyone going over how Bayesian classifiers work
做的好 你们现在知道了贝叶斯分类器的原理
I think I'm about time for me to hop back on screen
我想我现在可以回到屏幕啦
and give you some real-world examples of Bayesian classifiers
并给你一些贝叶斯分类器在真实世界应用的例子
and everyone did you miss me all right
好啦 你们想我了吗
so let's talk about our first example
让我们讲讲第一个例子吧
and that's spam
它就是识别垃圾邮件
Bayesian classifiers are used to figure out
贝叶斯分类器可以用来区别
whether or not email that you've received is spam or not
你收到的邮件是否是垃圾邮件
they're also used to classify whether or
它们也可用于检测
not your computer is affected or safe
你的计算机是否安全
they do this using probabilities of things that they know
它们通过已知概率来做到这一点
and then they go through the Bayesian classifier to
然后它们通过贝叶斯分类器
figure out whether or not you've been infected by a virus
能够知道计算机是否被病毒侵扰
how cool is that
多酷啊
all right everyone you've gone through Bayesian classifiers
好啦 你已经学习了贝叶斯分类器
you understand them inside and out
从内到外了解它们
you've also seen some great real-world examples of how they're used
你也看到了它们在现实生活中的应用
if you want to know more
如果你想要更多了解它
and you want to see it in action
看到它在实际生活中的应用
take a look at this video
看看这个视频
I hope all of you have gotten really interested in anti-viruses
我希望通过这节课的学习  你们所有人都对杀毒软件感兴趣
how they work and
知道它们的运作原理
how they can be used to help keep you safe
它们是如何保障计算机安全的
if you want to know even more
如果你还想知道更多
we've picked out some great books for you to check out
我们为你选了一些书
the first is antivirus hacker's handbook that's by Joxean Koret
第一本《antivirus hacker's handbook》作者是Joxean Koret
the next is Bayesian reasoning and machine learning by David barber
第二本是David Barber的《Bayesian reasoning and machine learning》
and the last one is the malware analyst cookbook and that's by Michael Ligh
最后一本是Michael Ligh的《the malware analyst cookbook》
any one of these books will teach
这些书中的任何一本都会教给
you so much more about anti viruses
你更多有关杀毒的知识
how they work and how they can be used to protect us
它们的工作原理以及它们是如何保护我们
so I hope you take the time to read one of them
所以我希望你能花时间好好读一读
alright everyone I want to talk about something really cool
现在我要说一个非常酷的东西
and that's the DARPA cyber grand challenge
那就是DRPPA网络挑战赛
this is actually like sports
它就像一个竞技比赛
and robots against each other for antivirus software
在这里 人们运用杀毒软件进行比拼
it's when artificial intelligence is pitted against artificial intelligence
这是人工智能与人工智能的比拼
what they tried to do was hack each other's systems
他们要做的就是黑进对方的系统
to see who was actually the most effective at preventing attacks
看看谁在防御进攻上最有效
now why is this important well
为什么这很重要
in computer security a revolution has started
在计算机安全领域 一场革命已经开始
where artificial intelligence is able to help
在这里 人工智能能够提供帮助
keep us more secure than ever and this
让我们比以往任何时候都更安全
competition really highlighted the
而这场比赛突出了
advances in machine learning space and
机器学习领域与人工智能领域
artificial intelligence space for antiviruses
在杀毒软件应用上的进步和发展
it proved that we have what it takes
它证明了我们有能力
to keep ourselves safe and secure
保护自己的安全
I want to take a moment to thank everyone for learning with me today
感谢今天和我一起学习
I hope you enjoyed learning more about viruses and anti viruses
希望你喜欢学习病毒与杀毒
I also want to let you know that
同时 我也想让你知道
if you're passionate about this
如果你对此抱有激情
you can help join that revolution of antivirus software
你也可以加入杀毒软件的革命浪潮之中
and you can help keep us more safe and more secure
你也可以帮助我们变得更安全